JONATHAN SOLARZ

(+972) 058-789-1350 | <u>ioni@solarz.me</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/ioni-solarz</u>

About me

Senior Architect with several years of experience in designing and developing turnkey solutions using different technologies. Experienced in leading technical teams for product development and technical projects, Software Development, requirement gathering, solution analysis and solution implementation.

Excellent communication skills that enable collaboration across global teams. Very focused on customer satisfaction to create solutions that meet their needs.

Experience

Solutions Architect Herzliya, Israel

Microsoft 2022 - CURRENT

- Led Azure Cloud, Data, and AI initiatives across the Middle East and Africa, empowering businesses to transform through technology. I bring deep expertise in delivering scalable, innovative solutions that meet complex business needs.
- Led Azure-based AI and data modernization projects across MEA, including a multi-phase AI Advisor enhancement that improved answer accuracy and reduced deployment time through CI/CD automation
- Designed and facilitated AI CoE, Devops and Agile workshops to accelerate Copilot and Agile adoption and LLMOps readiness for enterprise clients

Software Architect Petah Tikva, Israel
Bolt 2021 - 2021

- Led the modernization of the platform to .Net 6 & moved to Cloud first architecture.
- Created POCs that explore new technologies, assess their competence, and present recommendations to R&D leadership.
- Responsible for software architecture, bringing in advance solutions, methods, and tools. Solving issues of scalability, maintainability

Software Development Team Lead

Or Yehuda, Israel

2018 - 2021

- ImageSat International
 - Managed a team of 10: developers, QA, and DevOps
 - Applied the iDesign Method in coordination with the product team, increasing the product launch rate by 15%
 - Created, reviewed, and approved functional and technical design specifications for applications development.
 - Setup Azure DevOps CI/CD pipeline for testing, release and deploy, reducing deploy time by 60%
 - Mentored and trained team members to assist in completing tasks and meeting deadlines and business goals.
 - Designed the technical solution and developed a unified infrastructure for a multi satellite ground station.
 - Wrote the winning technical solution for a tender that increased the company's revenue by 30 million dollars.

Software Development Team Lead

Activetrail

Tel Aviv, Israel

2017 - 2018

- Managed a team of 5 developers.
 - Developed a messages service expanding sent messages by 50%
 - Setup Azure DevOps CI/CD pipeline for 30 servers reducing deploy time by 50%
 - Updated .Net version of existing software improving performance by 70%

Software Development Team Lead

Tel Aviv, Israel

2014 - 2017

- Tracx
 - Lead development team of 5 developers, QA and UI/UX expert
 - Designed, developed, and produced key features for the platform increasing revenue and client adoption by
 - Upgraded version control to Git, reducing new features development overhead by 50%
 - Wrote the technical architecture and design (SSD) of key features in the platform that allowed to validate the design and reduce development time by 25%

Software Developer

R/GA

Buenos Aires, Argentina

2011 - 2014

- Lead a development team of 3 developers, QA, and designer.
 - Developed solutions for company's clients: PWC, Microsoft, McCormick, Verizon, improving users reach by 25%
- Mentored and trained team members to assist in completing tasks and meet deadlines and business goals.
- Setup Azure services for testing, release and deploy, resulting in reducing testing time and faster release cycle.

Worked on the launch of Windows 8 increasing BA branch exposure and cooperation with US branches.

Software Development Team Lead

Buenos Aires, Argentina 2006 - 2011

Quadratica

- Managed a team of 3 developers working on different projects for our clients.
- Wrote requirements, technical design, implementation, testing, deployment, and documentation.
- Mentored and trained team members to assist in completing tasks and meet deadlines and business goals.

Software Developer

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Universidad de Flores

2001 - 2005

- Developed a new student management and billing system for the administration department.
- Developed a new course registration, exams, and academic queries system accessible through the university

Freelance and contracts

Software Developer

Edukana 2018 – 2019

- Worked as a software developer using React and Node
- Setup AWS services and servers and integrated with Bitbucket pipelines for testing, release and deploy.
- Extensive use of docker

Software Developer

LifeSkillGo 2017 - 2018

- Worked as a software developer using React and Node
- Setup AWS services and servers and integrated with GitLab pipelines for testing, release and deploy

Software Developer

Duglemmerdetaldrig

2015 - 2017

• Worked as a part time remote developer designing and developing the web application for the company using C# and .Net in general with AngularJS, Docker, Umbraco and MS SQL Server

Software Developer

Fressiel 2010 - 2015

- Created of a version of a George Harrison iOS App for Windows 8 using Metro App Style
- Worked on a prototype for doing 360 images with DSLR cameras, using Canon SDK and .NET built a 3D jQuery plugin to show the results.
- Customized Drupal and backend services for a IOS app

Contracts

Independent

- Building of a custom ERP for restaurants with analytics using .Net and Raven DB Database
- Freelance Developer for the Cabinet of Ministers of Argentina

Education and Training

Bachelor Computer Science

2006 – 2011

Universidad de Palermo

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Computer System Analyst

2000 – 2004

ORT .

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Skills

Architecture & Design

Solution Architecture | Enterprise Solutions Architecture | Solution Architecture Design | Technical Solution Architecture | Solution Building | Solutions Design | Solutions Integration | Agile methodologies

Cloud & DevSecOps

AWS, Azure | Git & DevOps CI/CD tools (GitHub, ADO, GitLab, Bitbucket) | Infrastructure as Code (IaC) | Docker

Software Development

C# / .NET 15+ years | Web Development 15+ years | Cloud native applications 7+ years | Relational and NoSQL databases 15+ years | React, Angular, Web Development | Python | PHP | Redis

Languages

Spanish | English | Hebrew